A Guide to the Governor Gerald L. Baliles Executive Papers, 1986-1990
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Gerald L. Baliles Executive Papers, 1986-1990
Library of Virginia
33702 and 33707
70.20 cubic feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Accession 33702 transferred from Office of the Governor, 11 January 1990; Accession 33707 transferred from Office of the Governor, 12 January 1990.
Biographical Information
Gerald L. Baliles was born in Patrick County, Virginia on 8 July 1940. He was educated in the public schools of Patrick County until high school when he attended Fishburne Military School in Waynesboro, Virginia and graduated in 1959. Baliles graduated from Wesleyan University in Connecticut in 1963 and received his law degree from the University of Virginia in 1967.
From 1967 to 1975, Baliles worked in the Virginia Attorney General's Office as an Assistant Attorney General and Deputy Attorney General. After leaving the Attorney General's Office in 1975, he joined the law firm of Partner, Bell, Lacey and Baliles and began his career in Democratic politics. He defeated incumbent Howard Carwile for the 35th District seat in the Virginia House of Delegates (representing Henrico County and the City of Richmond). Baliles served in the House of Delegates from 1976 to 1982.
In 1981, Baliles ran for Attorney General and narrowly defeated Wyatt B. Durrette, 50.9% to 49%, part of a Democratic sweep of the offices of Governor, Lieutenant Governor and Attorney General. Baliles served as Chairman of the Southern Association of Attorneys General and was selected as the most outstanding attorney general in the United States by his peers in the National Association of Attorneys General in 1985.
Baliles sought the governorship in 1985. He defeated Lieutenant Governor Richard Davis in the state party convention to win the Democratic gubernatorial nomination and once again defeated Wyatt B. Durrette in the general election, 55.2% to 44.8%. Baliles was sworn in on 11 January 1986 and became the sixty-fifth Governor of Virginia.
The Baliles administration focused primarily on transportation, trade and economic development and education. In 1986 appointed a Commission on Transportation for the 21st Century to study the Commonwealth's future transportation needs. That same year he convened a special session of the General Assembly that passed a 12 year $12 billion transportation package to modernize the state's roads, seaports, air ports, and mass transit, partially funded by a half cent increase in the sales tax. Baliles designated 1987 as the Year of Trade, established the Secretary of Economic Development and led eight international trade trips to promote Virginia in the international marketplace. Baliles education reforms included the introduction of guidance counselors in elementary schools and requirements for students to learn foreign languages.
During his term, Governor Baliles served as chairman of the Southern States Energy Board, Southern Growth Policies Boards (1987-1988), and National Governors' Association, 1988-1989.
After his term as Governor ended in January 1990, Baliles became a partner in the Richmond law firm, Hunton and Williams, where he focuses on aviation, trade and transportation law. Baliles has two children from his marriage to Jeannie P. Baliles, Laura and Jonathan. They divorced in 1996.
Scope and Content
Executive Papers, 1986-1990, including correspondence, form letters, memorandums, minutes, pamphlets, programs, reports, relating to Baliles term as governor. The majority of this collection consists of general correspondence from constituents to the Governor and an attached copy of the response of the Governor, Governor's Office, or the appropriate cabinet secretary or state agency. These records document the Governor's response to topical issues during the administration of Governor Gerald L. Baliles. In addition to mail from the general public (which includes invitations, requests for assistance on a variety of issues, and stances on policy), these records also include letters to and from federal and state agencies, local government officials, Virginia General Assembly members, member of the United States Congress, and others including the United States President, governors of other states and other members of Congress regarding legislative proposals, issues, and bills.
Correspondence from the Governor's Office, in addition to those written by Governor Baliles, include, David K. McCloud, Chief of Staff, 1986, Andrew B. Fogarty, Chief of Staff from 1986 to 1989, Leonard L. Hopkins, Jr., Chief of Staff from 1989 to 1990, H. Benson Dendy, III, Special Assistant to the Governor and Secretary to the Cabinet from 1986 to 1989, Patricia L. Lambeth, Alan D. Albert, Meredith L. Strohm, and Robert B. Jones, Jr., Special Assistants to the Governor.
Correspondence to and from Cabinet secretaries include, Carolyn J. Moss, Secretary of Administration from 1986 to 1990, Richard M. Bagley, Secretary of Commerce and Resources (1986) and Secretary of Economic Development from 1986-1988, Curry A. Roberts, Secretary of Economic Development from 1988 to 1990, Donald J. Finley, Secretary of Education from 1986 to 1990, Stuart W. Connock, Secretary of Finance from 1986 to 1989, Eva S. Teig, Secretary of Human Resources from 1986 to 1990, John W. Daniel, III, Secretary of Natural Resources from 1986 to 1990 and Vivian E. Watts, Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety from 1986 to 1990.
Correspondence to and from Virginia's Congressional delegation include Paul S. Trible, John W. Warner and Charles S. Robb.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series:
I. 1986
II. 1987
III. 1988
IV. 1989
V. 1990
VI. Miscellaneous
Series I through IV are each divided into the following sub-series:
A. General Correspondence
B. Associations
C. Localities
D. Governor's Office
E. Cabinet
F. General Assembly
G. Secretary of the Commonwealth
H. Legislative
I. Attorney General
J. Judicial
K. State Corporation Commission/Independent State Agencies
L. Lieutenant Governor
M. Virginia Liaison Office
N. United States Government
Contents List
- Series I: 1986 (accession 33702)
  Notable records include a letter to Leonard L. Hopkins, Jr., Executive Assistant to Governor Baliles from Joseph Gatins, a reporter from the Richmond Times Dispatch, dated 8 April 1986, concerning access to Governor Charles S. Robb's gubernatorial papers from 1982 and 1983. Attached is a memo to Governor Baliles from Hopkins, dated 6 April 1986 advising on same topic (Governor's Office, Staff Correspondence, Box 15, Folder 5); minutes of the Virginia State Mental Health and Mental Health Retardation Board from September 1985 to November 1986, copied to Governor (Cabinet, Secretary of Human Resources, Box 29); minutes of Virginia Health Services Cost Review Council from November 1985 to September 1986, copied to Governor (Cabinet, Secretary of Human Resources, Box 31, Folder 1); summary of ownership of all Virginia National Guard Armories as of 3 April 1986 (Cabinet, Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety, Dept. of Military Affairs, Box 37, Folder 6).
  - Sub-Series A: General Correspondence
    - Acid Rain (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - AIDS (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Agriculture (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Blood Drive (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Boy Scouts/Girl Scouts/Eagle Scouts (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Boys State of Virginia, American Legion (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Charity Lake Dam (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chesapeake Bay/Chesapeake Bay Foundation (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Child Care (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Drug and Alcohol Abuse (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Drunk Driving (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Eastern Virginia Medical School (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Education (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Flag Requests (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Flag Requests - No Flags (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Friendship Force (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - General (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Hands Across America (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Horse Center, Virginia (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - HOV - Northern Virginia and Virginia Beach (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Infant Mortality (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Literacy Parole Program (one of two) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Literacy Parole Program (two of two) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mandatory Seat Belt Law (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings - General (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - School Children's Letters - Samples (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - School Children's Requests (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Taxes - General (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Unanswered, Samples of (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - United Way Campaign (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Veterans and Veterans Cemetery (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Victims of Crime Act (VOCA) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Waterford Preservation (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Workfare (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series B: Associations
    - General (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Council of State Governments (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - National Governors' Association - Correspondence (one of two) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - National Governors' Association - Correspondence (two of two) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - National Governors' Association - Service Awards (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Southern Governors' Association - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Southern Governors' Association Council on International Education (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Southern States Energy Board (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Sub-Series C: Localities
    - Cities-General (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Counties-General (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Towns-General (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series D: Governor's Office
    - Advisory Board of Economists (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Birthday Congratulations (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Block Grants (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Budget (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Certificates of Recognition - See Messages from the Governor
    - Community Action Agencies (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Congratulations from the Governor (one of two) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Congratulations from the Governor (two of two) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Constituent Correspondence - See Staff Correspondence
    - Conventions & Meetings (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Get Well Letters (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Governor's Fellows Program (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 December 31 - November 24 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 November 21 - October 27 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 October 24 - August 22 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 August 21 - August 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 July 31 - July 9 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 July 8 - June 19 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 June 17 - May 29 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 May 28 - May 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 April 29 - April 11 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 April 10 - March 11 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 March 10 - February 12 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Governor's General Correspondence, 1986 February 10 - January 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Governor's Commission on Excellence in Education (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Governor's Commission on Efficiency in Government (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Organizational File (one of two) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Organizational File (two of two) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Correspondence, 1986 December 15 - November 12 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Correspondence, 1986 November 5 - October 21 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Correspondence, 1986 October 20 - October 8 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Correspondence, 1986 October 7 - September 23 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Correspondence, 1986 September 22 - September 13 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Correspondence, 1986 September 12 - September 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Correspondence, 1986 August 29 - June 10 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Correspondence, 1986 June 2 - April 28 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - [Governor's] Commission on Transportation in the 21st Century - Correspondence, 1986 April 23 - January 20 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Governor's Council on Alcohol and Drug Abuse (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Governor's Cup Fishing Tournament (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Governors - Other States (one of two) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Governors - Other States (two of two) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Granville Meade Scholarship (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Holton Commission/Washington Dulles Task Force (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Honorary Chairmanships & Memberships (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Inaugural Address, 1986 January 11, Senate Document 2a (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Inaugural Invitations and Programs (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Inaugural Participation, Thank You Letters from Governor Baliles (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - International Children's Festival (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Korea/United States Economic Council (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Legislative Tour - January 1986 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Liability Insurance (Tort Reform) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Literacy Program (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Mail Trends (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Messages from the Governor, 1986 January - April (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Messages from the Governor, 1986 May - August (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Messages from the Governor, 1986 September - December (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - [Messages from the Governor] - Certificates of Recognition, A-D & Partial Index (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - [Messages from the Governor] - Certificates of Recognition, E-L (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - [Messages from the Governor] - Certificates of Recognition, M-Q (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - [Messages from the Governor] - Certificates of Recognition, R-Z (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - [Messages from the Governor] - Proclamations (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - [Messages from the Governor] - See Also State of the Commonwealth Address
    - [Virginia] Military Advisory Commission (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Model General Assembly - YMCA (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - News Clippings (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Poplar Forest (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Proclamations - See Messages from the Governor
    - Requests, Samples of (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Requests, Auction (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Resignations (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Retirement Letters (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - School for the Gifted (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Staff Correspondence (Constituent Correspondence) - See Also Form Letters (Boxes 17-19)
    - Staff Correspondence (Constituent Correspondence) - Patricia Lambeth, Special Assistant, 1986 December 29 - August 14 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Staff Correspondence (Constituent Correspondence) - Patricia Lambeth, Special Assistant, 1986 August 13 - May 22 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Staff Correspondence (Constituent Correspondence) - Patricia Lambeth, Special Assistant, 1986 May 21 - April 1 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Staff Correspondence (Constituent Correspondence) - Patricia Lambeth, Special Assistant, 1986 March 31 - March 12 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Staff Correspondence (Constituent Correspondence) - Patricia Lambeth, Special Assistant, 1986 March 11 - February 17 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Staff Correspondence (Constituent Correspondence) - Patricia Lambeth, Special Assistant, 1986 February 14 - February 7 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Staff Correspondence (Constituent Correspondence) - Patricia Lambeth, Special Assistant, 1986 February 6 - January 13 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1986 December 31 - November 24 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1986 November 21 - September 24 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1986 September 21 - July 1 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1986 June 30 - April 17 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1986 April 10 - January 8 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - State of the Commonwealth Address, 1986 January 13, Senate Document No. 2B (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Sympathy Letters (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Tax-exempt Bonds (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Telegrams (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Thank You Letters from the Governor (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Thank You Letters to the Governor, 1986 December 29 - July 2 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Thank You Letters to the Governor, 1986 June 20 - January 20 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Commission on the Bicentennial of the United States Constitution (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Cultural Laureates (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Military Advisory Commission - See Military Advisory Commission
    - The Virginia Silver Star Organization (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Wedding Congratulations (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Lynchburg Work Week (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Northern Virginia Work Week (one of three) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Northern Virginia Work Week (two of three) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Northern Virginia Work Week (three of three) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Roanoke Work Week (one of two) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Roanoke Work Week (two of two) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Form Letters 86-2 thru 5 (includes list of 1986 Form Letters) (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Form Letters 86-6 thru 9 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Form Letters 86-10 thru 13 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Form Letters 86-14 thru 17 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Form Letters 86-18 thru 20 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Form Letters 86-21 thru 23 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Form Letters 86-24 thru 27 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Form Letters 86-28 thru 30 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Form Letters 86-31 thru 32 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Form Letters 86-33 thru 34 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Form Letters 86-35 thru 37 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Form Letters 86-38 thru 41 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Form Letters 86-42 thru 44 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Form Letters 86-45 thru 50 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Form Letters 86-51 thru 55 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Form Letters 86-56 thru 60 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Form Letters 86-61 thru 66 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series E: Cabinet
    - General (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Meetings and Agendas (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - E.1 - Secretary of Administration
    - Correspondence and Memorandums to Governor's Office, 1986 December 17-August 1 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and Memorandums to Governor's Office, 1986 July 28-January 20 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Copied to Governor's Office Staff, 1986 December 17-May 5 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Office Automation (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - E.1 - Secretary of Administration - State Agencies
    - Commission on Local Government (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Compensation Board (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Department of General Services (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Department of Information Technology (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Department of Personnel and Training (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Department of Personnel and Training - Virginia Executive Institute (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - State Board of Elections (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Supplemental Retirement System (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - E.2 - Secretary of Economic Development (Secretary of Commerce and Resources from January-July 1986)
    - Correspondence and Memorandums sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1986 December 30-June 2 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Memorandums sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1986 May 28-February 5 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Deputy Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence and Memorandums sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - E.2 - Secretary of Economic Development - State Agencies
    - Department of Commerce (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Department of Economic Development, 1986 December 17-September 16 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Department of Economic Development, 1986 September 15-January 6 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Department of Economic Development - Southeast United States/Japan Association (SEUS/Japan), Annual Meeting at The Homestead, Hot Springs, Va., 1986 October 12-14 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Department of Economic Development - Small Business Finance Authority (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Department of Economic Development - Division of History (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Department of Economic Development - Virginia Film Office (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Department of Housing and Community Development (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Department of Housing and Community Development - Main Street Program (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Department of Labor and Industry (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Southern Growth Policies Board (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Southwest Virginia Economic Development Commission (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Employment Commission, 1986 December 30-July 1 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Employment Commission, 1986 June 18-January 7 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Housing Development Authority (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - E.3 - Secretary of Education
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1986 December 30-September 12 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1986 September 9-July 14 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1986 July 11-May 8 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1986 December 30-September 12 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Memorandums sent or copied to Governor's Office, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - E.3 - Secretary of Education - Colleges and Universities
    - Council for Higher Education (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Christopher Newport University (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - George Mason University (See Also Oversize Box 1) (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - James Madison University (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Longwood College (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Mary Washington College (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Medical College of Virginia - See Virginia Commonwealth University
    - Norfolk State University (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Old Dominion University (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Old Dominion University - Virginia Center for World Trade (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Radford University (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - University of Virginia (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Commonwealth University/Medical College of Virginia (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Community College System (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Military Institute (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Virginia State University (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - College of William and Mary (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - E.3 - Secretary of Education - Education Topics
    - Adult Basic Education (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Carnegie Report on Education (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Education Commission of the States (ECS) (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Elementary School Guidance Counselors (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Museum of American Frontier Culture (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - School Health Clinics (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Southeastern Universities Research Association (SURA)/Continuous Electronic Beam Accelerator Facility (CEBAF) (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Southern Center for International Studies (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Southern Regional Education Board (SREB) (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Standards of Quality (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - State Board of Education (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Superconducting Super Collider (SSC) (Box 25, Folder 9)